

Flamur Kasa

Date of birth: 28 Oct 1991

Nationality: Macedonian/citizen of the Republic of North Macedonia

CONTACT







ABOUT ME

Besides the work I have done for my employers, I have written scripts to automate and make it easier for me and people around me to get repetitive or frequent tasks done. I enjoy learning new technologies and frameworks to make interesting and useful applications to empower users and make their lives easier. I try to use all my experience when fixing problems which sometimes leads to "outside-the-box" solutions given my diverse repertoire of tools and tricks I have accrued over the years.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FEB 2019 - JUN 2021 - Kichevo, North Macedonia

Head of IT

National Institute Cultural Center "Kocho Racin" - Kichevo

While at the cultural center Koch Racin I have worked on:

- creating and maintaining a three-lingual WordPress website
- training staff on using the CMS, work emails and Slack
- designing posters and creating video ads for events
- maintaining the IT infrastructure of the institution
- producing cultural events for Facebook live streams (song festivals, concerts, book promotions)
- book cover designs

https://kultura-k.com

APR 2015 - JUN 2017 - Tirana, Albania

Full stack developer (WAMP)

Blueberry (Google Partner)

While at Blueberry, I was the main full-stack developer (WAMP) on the in-house PHP MVC internal platform which was used by over 100 employees from different departments. Some of the tasks I worked on included:

- adding features and expanding the platform such as integrating the Google Adwords API to track the performance of our clients and generate reports directly through our system
- setting up an automatic task handling system to streamline the workflow for each department
- creating browser extensions to integrate with 3rd party websites from partners
- optimising the MySQL database bottlenecks after a significant increase in new clients and employee count
- interviewing PHP developers to expand our team + mentoring new hires until independent

https://blueberry.al/

https://web.archive.org/web/20190122161546/https://blueberry.al/ #archived-version

FEB 2016 - NOV 2017 - Online

Freelance Developer

While freelancing, I have worked on:

- creating video landing pages with custom player features
- expanding analytics dashboards (frontend + backend)
- creating a browser extension to automate the exporting of emails, time needed reduced from 5 hours to 5 seconds
- writing scripts to handle, sort, split and clean email lists with millions of rows
- creating a browser extension to circumvent censoring

 creating a browser extension to fake geolocation to simulate local Google search results

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2012 - 2015 - North Macedonia

Bachelors in Computer Science

South East European University

The studies program was all done in English.

During my studies, I also completed the mandatory internship at three different companies (one month at each company).

EQF level 6 | ECTS | 180 | https://www.seeu.edu.mk/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Albanian

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

English - language of university studies

Listening C1	Reading C2	Spoken production C1	Spoken interaction C1	Writing C1
French - DELF B2				
Listening B2	Reading B2	Spoken production B2	Spoken interaction B2	Writing B2
German				
Listening A1	Reading A1	Spoken production A1	Spoken interaction A1	Writing A1

DRIVING LICENCE



Driving Licence: B

VOLUNTEERING

NOV 2017 - OCT 2019

Volunteer

Youth Development Organization FACTOR, Kichevo, North Macedonia As a volunteer at FACTOR, I have contributed by:

- designing certificates for participants of our various activities
- programmatically generating certificates from text lists (some activities had over 100 participants)
- leading classrooms with over 30 children during our week long educational English summer camps
- creating and assisting with the activities of the educational English summer camps
- providing tech support throughout my volunteering period
- representing our organisation in various national and international NGO events
- personally coordinating and hosting programming and internet safety event for the youth of our town
- promoting our various events to various schools in our city and surrounding villages
- participating and taking local youth to week long training session abroad (Vienna, Austria)

https://www.facebook.com/Youth-Development-Organisation-Factor-1527942647513523/

JUN 2020 - CURRENT

Programming Node.js Discord bot for YouTube live show audience interaction

Online

I became the producer of a YouTube live show in June 2020. I programmed a Node.js bot on Discord to:

- interact with the audience
- display approved questions on the show
- show charts of votes and other information collected from the audience
- show points during the game show
- handle speaking permissions for show guests and audience questions
- create connection tunnels for the host to remotely control the scenes of the show through their tablet
- handle the game show teams, scores and game mechanics We created 167 video in 6 months (6.3 videos/week on average). At our peak, we had 4 different cameras (phones) in the USA sending their feed to my computer in North Macedonia which streamed the show on 5 different platforms simultaneously (YouTube, Facebook, Twitter, Discord and Twitch).

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UClkT332HEYPO8xvRXOhQrXghttps://github.com/Street-Epistemology/thermometer